Guide to the Houston Area Asian Archives oral history interviews and related materials, 2003-2021 MS 573
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Oral history interview by last name, N-Z
  - Tran, Michelle, 159652 (Box 10)
    Includes audio, transcript, and photograph.
  - Truong, Tanya Pham, 123467 (Box 10)
    Includes audio and transcript.
  - Tsai, Ming-Jer, 2018-08-20 (Box 10)
  - Tsai, Sophia (restricted until 2038), 2018-06-14 (Box 10)
    This interview is restricted by donor request until 2038, when it may be made available publicly. Until then, it is maintained in the Woodson Research Center's nearline environment, at identifier MS0573aip_001.
  - Tu, Huynh Cong, 2018-07-07 (Box 10)
  - Lucita Villamiel oral history, 2014-03-13; 181533 (Box 10)
  - Vu, Phong (no audio), 174337 (Box 10)
  - Wallick, Okpun, 159656 (Box 10)
    Includes audio, transcript, survey, and photograph.
  - Denka Wangdi, 2017-11 (Box 10)
  - Wani, Manish, 2018-04-04 (Box 10)
  - Watanabe, Daniel, 132942 (Box 10)
  - Wo, Helen, 174351 (Box 10)
    Includes consent form, questionnaire, transcript, and research notes.
  - Dr. Ed Wong, 2016 (wrc08330) (Box 10)
  - Wong, Michael, 2018-12-07 (Box 10)
  - Wong, Martha, 132878 (Box 10)
    Includes news article, resume, survey, transcript, and audio.
  - Stephen Bryan Wong oral history, 2014-03-24; 181538 (Box 10)
  - Eugene Wu oral history, 172594 (Box 10)
    Includes consent form, research notes, transcript, and photograph.
  - Linda Gee Wu oral history, 172569 (Box 10)
    Includes transcript, photographs, consent form, and photographs of family documents, newsclippings, correspondence and publications related to Chinese American Citizens Alliance and the Miss Chinatown competition in Houstion.
  - Wu, Samuel, 2019-04-14 (Box 11)
  - Theodore Wu oral history interview (wrc05767), 260395 (Box 11)
    Includes consent form and photographs.
  - Zhenkand Xu oral history, 2014-05-30; 181543 (Box 11)
  - Lewis Yee, June 15, 2010, 114914 (Box 11)
    Includes transcript.
  - Yingchao Yi oral history, 168361 (Box 11)
  - Dr. K. Casey Youn, 160618 (Box 11)
    Includes transcript, questionnare, audio, and consent form.
  - Young, Mary Ann Gee, 2017-10-02 (Box 11)
  - Weiwei Zhong oral history, 168365 (Box 11)
  - Zhou, Jane, 174345 (Box 11)
    Includes transcript, research notes, questions, and consent form.
  - Anonymous, Summer 2014 (wrc05137) (Box 11)
    ZAH. Includes photographs, transcript, amd research notes.
  - Zheng, Tairong, 2017-06-08 (Box 11)
  - Wong, Connie Kwan, oral history, 2019-07-31 (Box 11)
  - Verma, Kiran, oral history, 2019-07-29 (Box 11)
  - Yoshiyama, Charles Louis, oral history, 2019-08-19 (Box 11)
  - Wang, Don, 2019-06-14 (Box 11)
  - Pabillano, Anthony, 2020-03-08
    Also includes awards, certificates, and event programs featuring Pabillano.
  - Yao, Janie, 2019-12-12 (Box 11)
    Also includes newsclippings.
- Series III: Subject files and photographs unrelated to specific interviews, 159773 (Box 12-13)
  - Forbidden City images, 28 black and white images, 159774 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hope Clinic brochure (HOPE - Helping Other People Through Encouragement) a community health center funded by the Asian American Health Coalition of Greater Houston. Ca. 2011., 159775 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - OCA Greater Houston magazine "4a", Fall 2011 issue (OCA - Organization of Chinese Americans), 159776 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Community Forum: Immigration and Citizenship Workshop Flyer, 2012, 159777 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Photograph: Gerald Young, of the Flying Tigers, World War II, 159778 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Photograph: Elder members of the Chinese Jamaican community, ca. 1940, 159779 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Photograph: Street scene of World War II victory parade of Chinese Jamaicans honoring Chiang, in Kingston, Jamaica, 159780 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Liu, Chieh-min: United States Army Air Corps Training Center diploma certifying Liu Chieh-min as a trained airplane pilot, 1943, 159783 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Liu, Chieh-min: Authorization from Chiang Kai-shek (Jiang Zhongzheng) to Accept Training in the USA (written in Chinese), 159782 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Liu, Chieh-min: Arizona Drivers License, 1943 (image of), 159784 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Japanese American Citizens League website pages as captured by George Hirasaki, November 2010 (on cd-rom and printed on paper), 164785 (Box 12, Folder 11-23)
    Includes chapter history (folder 11), miscellaneous activism (folder 12), services provided by JACL (folder 13), miscellaneous administrative records (folder 14), miscellaneous events (folder 15), Abbie Salyers Grub's paper (folder 16), 65th anniversary presentation (folder 17), Texas state board of education (folder 18), tpm (folder 19), responses (folder 20), pictures (folder 21), Japan fest 2008 (folder 22), and Gala 2009 (folder 23).
  - Panis, Francisco: WWII United States Army Forces in the Far East, 160663 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Video interview, ca. 2005 (no transcript) (disc in box, not yet online per consent form needs - request further identifying info from donor), 160664
    - Program from posthumous military medal ceremony and screening of film "Forgotten Soliders," 2012, 160665
  - C. Y. Chu documents and realia, 1920-1936, 166543 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - John (Chong) Henry Eng documents regarding WWII service (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Albert Gee clippings and ephemera related to his restaurant businesses, including the Poly-Asian Club. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Also includes commemorative plate inscribed "Tuesday, October 16, 1962, Epicurean Evening, Your Host, Houston Restaurant Association" and is believed to be the plate presented to Albert Gee, who in 1961 was the first the first Asian-American president of the Houston Restaurant Association (HRA). Donated by Dr. Anne Chao, to whom the plate was presented in 2021 by the HRA.
  - Rudolfo Hulen Fernandex, first known Asian graduate from Rice, 1917 - newsclippings (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Photograph of interior of Chungking Restaurant, Jensen Dr and Caplin St., Houston, TX, circa 1940s (Box 12, Folder 29)
    Chungking Restaurant was owned by Jim Wing, who was one of the first Chinese in Houston, arriving circa 1895. The Jim Wing family was part of the Joe family, and Jim Wing helped many Joe family members move to Houston and Texas. Wing owned many restaurants in downtown Houston, 1930s-1940s.
  - Time magazine featuring on cover: "Madame Chiang: She and China know what endurance means" March 1, 1943 (Box 13)
  - Life magazine, featuring on cover "China's Madame Chiang," June 30, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Beverly Gor awards
    - Outstanding Preceptor Award (2013): Plaque from the Houston Academy of Nutrition & Dietetics presented to Dr. Beverly Gor (Box 13)
    - Certificate of Appreciation (?): Presented from the USDA Center for Nutrition Policy and Promotion, recognizing Dr. Beverly Gor's work with CAN DO Houston (Box 13)
    - Certificate of Appreciation (04/29/13): Presented during Health Awareness Month recognizing Dr. Beverly Gor's "invaluable community service promoting health equity and reducing health disparities" (Box 13)
    - Outstanding Preceptor Award Veteran (2013): Award presented from the Texas Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics to Dr. Beverly Gor (Box 13)
    - TDA Media Award (2007): Plaque presented from the Houston Area Dietetic Association (Box 13)
    - Nursing Excellence: Problem Solving, Populations, and Performance (July 27, 2014): Plaque recognizing Dr. Beverly Gor for Presenting "Health and Cancer needs of Asian Pacific Islanders: Stories from the 'Model Minority'" (Box 13)
    - Wooden Frame with Script (?): Text in Chinese (Box 13)
    - Appreciation Plaque (March, 2004): Plaque from the Houston Department of Health and Human Services "in appreciation of [Dr. Gor's] time and support of [the] WIC Nutrition Education Program" (Box 13)
    - Origami Frame (June, 2007): Presented from the Asian American Health Coalition/HOPE Clinic "in appreciation for [Dr. Gor's] selfless dedication and servant leadership in establishing HOPE Clinic" (Box 13)
    - Framed Newspaper Article (01/25/02): Text in Chinese (Box 13)
    - National Forensic League Certification (11/18/70): Award certifying that Dr. Gor was elected as a member of the National Forensic Leage at Houston-Milby (Box 13)
    - Certificate of Appreciation (07/27/02): Presented from the Stand Against Violence Everyone Alief organization for Dr. Gor's contributions to the Alief Health and Civic Resources Fair. (Box 13)
    - Certificate of Appreciation (07/19/00): Presented to Dr. Gor from the Texas Health Steps Outreach Workgroup for her guest presentation "Reaching Out to the Outreach Worker" (Box 13)
    - Seminar Speaker Plaque (July 4, 2009): Presented from the Federation of Bangladeshi Associations in North America to Dr. Gor for her work as the Seminar Speaker at the FOBANA 2009 Convention (Box 13)
    - University of Texas Graduation Appreciation Award (2004): Presented from Rachel Gor to her parents for "...helping [her] to attain this most important milestone of [her] life" (Box 13)
    - Distinguished Dietitian Award (2004): Presented by Jill Campbell of the Houston Area Dietetic Association to Dr. Beverly Gor (Box 13)
    - Recognition Award (2004): Presented from the Texas Cancer Council in recognition for Dr. Gor's service to the Texas Cancer Plan Update Project (Box 13)
  - Tommy Ligh family tree (Box 14)
  - Artwork by Sherry Tseng Hill, "Forgive but not forget," acrylic painting on canvas board, 2020 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Dimensions 48" (W) x 18" (H) x 3" (T). Original work stored in Woodson vault. Folder contains a printed image of the painted work.
  - Hella Bubble boba tea cup and newsclip for best Boba / teahouse in Houston, June 2020, donated by owner Titan Huang (Box 15)